Guide to the Alice Park Papers, 1920-1936
Department of Special Collections
Alice Park Papers,
1920-1936
Special Collections M0105
Park, Alice
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Alice Park.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, pamphlets, newsclippings and flyers pertaining to the subject of birth control and planned parenthood. Correspondents include Mary Ware Dennett, Margaret Sanger, Albert P. Van Dusen, the American Birth Control League, and the Voluntary Parenthood League.
Biographical Note
Alice Park was an American pacifist, a feminist and a socialist.
For additional material see Hoover Institution and The Huntington Library.
Container List
- Correspondence (Folder 1)
  - 1920, Dec 30.AP to Mary Ware Dennett, 1 p carbon copy.
  - 1920, Mar 5.Margaret Sanger to AP, 1 p. TLS.
  - 1921, Jan 7.MWD to AP, 1 p. TLS.
  - 1922, Mar 31.Anne Kennedy (American Birth Control League) to AP, 1 p. TLS.
  - 1922, Jun 26.MWD to AP, 2 pp. TLS.
  - 1924, Oct 26.MWD to AP, 2 pp. ALS.
  - 1925, Feb 17.Margaret Sanger to AP, 1 p. TLS.
  - [1929]MS to MWD, 2 pp. Carbon copy TL.
  - 1926, Oct 29.Mary Summer Boyd (American Birth Control League) to AP, 1 p. TLS.
  - 1927, May 22.Vine McCasland to AP, 2 pp, ALS.
  - 1925, Dec 2.Myra P. Gallert (Voluntary Parenthood League) to member, 4 pp, TL.
  - 1929, Apr 16.Carl Rave (open letter), 1 p, TL. (2 copies)
  - 1930, Jan 28.Margaret Sanger to [?], 1 p, TLS.
  - 1930, Nov 7.Albert P. Van Duren to AP, 1 p, ALS
  - 1936, May 26.Margaret Sanger to AP, 1 p, TLS.
- Pamphlets on birth control, (16) (Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous (Folder 3)
  - Newsclips, (3)
  - Member lists of Northern California Birth Control Committee of One Hundred., (4 pp)
  - Flyers (1 dup) and announcement.
- 1934 Sep 27,Peninsula Section, Vol 1, #3. (Folder 4)
  [4. through 11. are miscellaneous editions of Upton Sinclair's Epic News.]
- 1934 Aug 14,Palo Alto, Vol 1, #1. (Folder 5)
- 1934 Oct 11,Santa Clara County, Vol 1, #1. (Folder 6)
- 1934 Jul 28- Dec 4,San Francisco, Vol 1, #1,2,3,6,[7]. (Folder 7)
- 1934 Jul 23,Los Angeles, Vol 1, #9.
- 1934 Oct 22,Special Edition Issue, Vol 1, #1. (Folder 8)
- 1934,19th Assembly district, Vol 1, #13. (Folder 9)
- 1934 Sep 25,52nd Assembly district, Vol 1, #5. (Folder 10)
- 1934 Oct 11,64th District, Vol 1, #8. (Folder 11)
- Upton Sinclair's End Poverty Paper. (Othertype Oversize folder)
  - [1933-34?] Dec 26 - Jan 2.Los Angeles/San Francisco, Vol 1, #1.
  - 1934 FebLos Angeles/San Francisco, Vol 1, #1.
  - 1934 MarLos Angeles/San Francisco, Vol 1, #3.
  - 1934 MarLos Angeles/San Francisco, Vol 1, #4.
  - 1934 AprLos Angles/San Francisco, Vol 1, #5.
  - 1934 MayLos Angeles, Vol 1, #6.
  - 1934 MayLos Angeles, Vol 1, #7.
  - 1935 MarLos Angeles, Vol 1, #3.
  - [1935] AprLos Angeles, Vol 2, #1.
  - [1935] MayLos Angeles, Vol 2, #2.
Both the End Poverty Paper and Epic News were originally given to the Hoover Institution by Alice Park and later transferred to the Manuscripts Division of Special Collections, Stanford University Libraries.